Like Carrey said, you might want to use a cohort,
就像 Carrey 说的 根据你关注的问题类型
depending on the type of problem you are looking at.
你可能想要使用列队
A cohort makes more sense than looking at the entire population,
有时候 关注列队比关注总体更有意义
if you're looking for learning effects, if you're examining user retention,
例如你想研究学习效果或者用户留存情况
if you want to increase user activity, or
你想增加用户活动
anything else that requires the user to be established for some reason.
或者研究其他因某些原因需要确定用户的课题
Going back to the Audacity example,
回头看优达学城的例子
here's a situation where they might need to use a cohort.
在这种情况下 他们可能需要使用队列
Suppose they have an existing course that's already up and running.
假设他们已开设并正在提供某门课程
Some students have completed the course, other students are midway through, and
有些学员完成了这门课程 有些学员差不多学到了一半
there are students who have not yet started.
还有些学员尚未参加
They want to try changing the structure of one of the lessons
他们想试着调整其中一节课的结构
to see if it improves the completion rate of the entire course.
以便了解是否能改善整个课程的完成率
Now, because they want to see, what happens throughout the course where
因为他们想了解的是
students can pause or unpause the lessons,
学员会在课程发生什么情况时暂停或取消暂停一节课
switch devices, etc., the unit of diversion will need to be a user-id.
例如更换设备之类的 那么他们将使用用户 ID 作为分组单元
That said, it doesn't make sense to just run the experiment on
也就是说 直接对所有参加课程的学员进行实验
all the users in the course.
是没有意义的
To see that, suppose that this blue line shows the time that students start
为此 我们假设这条蓝线代表学员参加优达学城想调整结构的那节课的时间
the lessons that Audacity is changing with later times to the right.
右边为更近的时间
Each purple dot represents a user or student.
每个紫色点代表一个学员
So, at this time four students started the lesson at the same time.
在这时候 有四个学员同时参加了这节课
Now, suppose that Audacity starts running the experiment at this time, for
假设优达学城在这时候
students who started the lesson a while ago,
对此前加入这节课的学员开始进行实验
they may actual have finished the lesson already.
他们可能已经完成了这节课
So, they're already past that lesson, and
他们可能已经通过了这节课的考试
they're not even going to see the change.
从而他们根本看不到课程的变化
So, taking this whole population of user-ids, and
所以优达学城并不想
running the experiment on them, isn't what Audacity wants.
对所有这些用户 ID 总体进行实验
Instead, it would make sense to use a cohort, and only include users who
更合理的方法是使用队列
started the lesson after the experiment was started in the experiment.
仅对在实验开始后参加这节课的学员进行实验
That is, it's a subset of the population, who have the shared
这是总体的一个子集 这些学员拥有参加新结构的课程这一共同经历
experience of receiving the new lesson, and not seeing the old lesson.
而且都没有见过旧结构的课程
Now, for the control, Audacity needs to create a comparable cohort.
作为对照 优达学城需要创建一个可供对比的队列
They can not just use these users,
他们不能直接将这些
who are not included in the experiment as the control because there may have
没有进入实验的用户作为对照
been other system changes in that time that affected the new users.
因为那时候可能存在其他一些对新用户产生影响的系统变化
So, instead, Audacity will need to split this cohort into an experiment cohort
优达学城需要将这个队列
and a control cohort, so
拆分为一个实验队列和一个对照队列
that they all have the same timing of when they started the lesson.
他们参加课程的时间相同
Now, in this example, we chose a cohort based on time, but
在这个例子中 我们根据时间选择列队
you could also use other factors to create a cohort.
但你可以根据其他因素来创建队列
Just like running your experiment only on New Zealand, using a cohort is
就像仅对新西兰进行实验一样
limiting your experiment to a subset of your population.
使用队列就相当于限制为对总体的一个子集进行实验
Thus, in the same way,
因此 使用队列将以相同的方式
using a cohort can affect the variability of your metric.
影响你所用指标的差异性